extension.org 2018-12-27

# eXtension Privacy Policy – eXtension

_(Updated 22 May 2018)_

Your privacy is important to eXtension Foundation (“ **eXtension** ”). This privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) provides you with information regarding the personal information collected during your visits to this eXtension website (the “ **Site** ”), how it is used, with whom it may be shared and what choices you have regarding collection and distribution of your personal information. This site is not intended to be used by residents either outside the U.S. or within the EU/UK.

eXtension reserves the right, at any time, to modify this Privacy Policy. If eXtension makes revisions that change the way we collect, use, or share personal information, we will post those changes in this Privacy Policy. You should review this Privacy Policy periodically so that you keep up to date on our most current policies and practices. We will note the effective date of the latest version of our Privacy Policy at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

**What personal information may be collected?**

eXtension collects personal information when users voluntarily submit it to us.  For example, when you register with eXtension, we collect personal information, including your name and address. We may also ask for information about your areas of interest to provide relevant resources to better serve your needs. You may choose not to share your geographical information or areas of interest, but we encourage you to do so to receive a more personalized experience with eXtension.

Unregistered users of eXtension must provide their e-mail address and name when providing a comment or asking a question.

**How will my information be used?**

Information provided by unregistered users may be used to follow-up on the particular question or comment from the user. Users have the option to register or opt-in to receive additional information or communications from eXtension.

For registered users, information collected during registration may be used to provide tailored information and resources for each user based on areas of interest and geographical location. Geographical information may be used to provide a customized home page featuring relevant local information and news. Information collected on your areas of interest may be used to provide you with publications and news related to your interests on your personalized home page. Registered users have the option to allow eXtension to share your personal information with local Extension offices to better serve your needs. You may also choose to receive local Extension newsletters and other communications. To ensure your privacy, you will be provided with a way to unsubscribe from any newsletters you may receive.

**Information sharing and disclosure**

We do not share or sell your personal information to third parties except as described in this Privacy Policy. Registered users will have the choice to opt-out of any sharing of personal information with our partner universities or local eXtension offices. eXtension may share your personal information with service providers that perform services for eXtension, such as providing marketing assistance and analyzing data. For example, we use cookies at extension.org from service providers such as Google Analytics to collect user traffic data. There may also be instances when eXtension may disclose your personal information without providing you with a choice in order to protect the legal rights of eXtension, our partner universities or local eXtension offices, agents, and employees; to honor a request that you have made through the Site; to protect the safety and security of other users; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with the law or legal process.

While browsing the eXtension Site, you may sometimes encounter links to other companies or agencies that are not controlled by eXtension or its partners. Please be aware that eXtension is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be cautious when leaving the eXtension Site and carefully read the privacy statements of other websites.

If you make a comment, use a bulletin board or chat room on the eXtension Site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Access to personal information**

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer want to be a part of the eXtension Site, you may correct, update, or deactivate it by making the change on your account information page or by emailing eXtension at [privacy@extension.org](mailto:privacy@extension.org).

**Choice/Opt-Out**

You may use the eXtension Site without registering. Some features require you to input your name and e-mail address in order to receive follow-up from eXtension. When you register to use the eXtension Site, you will be asked to share personal information that will allow you to receive a personalized experience on the Site. You may choose not to share information other than your name and e-mail address. We provide you the opportunity to “opt-out” of having your personal information used for certain purposes, including sharing your information with local Extension offices or tailoring your experience based on your geolocation, when we ask for this information.

If you choose to receive local newsletters or other communications and later decide you no longer wish to subscribe, you may opt out of receiving them by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each newsletter.

Some web browsers permit you to broadcast a preference that you not be “tracked” online. At this time, eXtension does not modify your experience on the Site based upon whether such a signal is broadcast.

**Security**

We are committed to protecting the personal information you submit to us, and we employ reasonable security measures to protect your personal information from being disclosed to individuals who are not described in this Privacy Policy. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. While we strive to use reasonable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Children’s Privacy**

eXtension Foundation is committed to protecting the privacy of children. eXtension will never knowingly request personal information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent.

**Contact information**

If you have any questions regarding eXtension’s Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with eXtension, please contact eXtension at [privacy@extension.org](mailto:privacy@extension.org).

If eXtension needs, or is required, to contact you concerning any event that involves information about you, we may do so by email, telephone, or mail.
